ANDRÉ AUSTVOLL

UX/UI/XR Designer

+47 96 94 41 53

a.austvoll@gmail.com

Oslo, Norge

Pf aaustvoll.myportfolio.com

in linkedin.com/in/andre-austvoll/

EDUCATION

Certificate,

UX Design Immersion

CareerFoundry, 2020 - 2021

Master of Arts (MA), Somatic studies & Laban movement analysis Univ of Surrey 2003 - 2005

SKILLS

- UX/UI design
- XR & Spatial Interaction Design
- Storyboarding & sketching
- Design Thinking
- User Journeys
- User & Competitor Research
- Persona Creation
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Design Presentations
- Frontend (HTML, CSS & JS)

SOFTWARE

- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Unity
- Visual Studio Code
- Premiere Pro
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Gravity Sketch
- Blender
- Hotjar

LANGUAGES

- Norwegian
- English
- German
- French

PROFILE

I am specialised in visual and UX design and love to create solutions based on user-centred processes and business value. In my work I have achieved usability improvements and revenue increases for high profile clients, designed web applications, augmented and virtual reality experiences, videochat and streaming solutions.

EXPERIENCE

SEENTHIS, UX/UI Designer, Web & Technical Producer 2022 - now

Responsible for technical production for video streaming, interaction design UX and frontend. Resolving challenges on short deadlines and contributing to creative problem solving in UX evaluations, wireframing & prototyping.

- User oriented visual and experience design
- Developing in HTML5, CSS and Javascript
- Using apps like Visual Studio Code Designing, Adobe (Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects & XD) & Figma.
- Clients include IKEA, Telia, Cubus, Opel, Hydro, Bergans & sBanken

VIDEOUTSTYR NORGE AS, Video Solutions Designer, 2011 - 2022

Advised video streaming and virtual reality clients in broadcast and video production, government, education, industry & medical.

- Acted as product manager for Virtual Reality and 360 video. Identified 35 products leading to increased revenue in the field by almost 2 000%.
- Led the development of a 360/virtual reality underwater surveillance solution for fish farms and visitor centres.
- Redesigned UX/UI of webshop, optimised storage system and automated order flow, expediting the orders for more than 200 custom products.
- Negotiated deals with companies in more than 6 countries including China, USA, Czech Republic, Germany, New Zealand and UK

MICRODANCE, XR/UX/UI & Spatial Interaction Designer 2001 - 2011

Started business, designing spatial interactions, producing video and dance performances, workshops, choreography and behavioural research.

- Freelanced on spatial interaction, frontend and user experience design.
- Conducted international projects in more than 9 countries including Brazil, China, Finland, Norway, Poland, Russia, Slovenia, England & USA.
- Managed and evaluated creative and technical project teams.

CANON, User research and marketing

2009 - 2011

I acted as dealer contact with responsibility for product and user experiences as well as marketing of cameras and photographic printers in the field.

- Evaluated user feedback and goals for professional video products sales.
- Performed on-site follow-up of resellers around mid and south Norway.
- Did product management, field demonstrations, documentation of shop displays and acquired user feedback.